[Music]
What does it really take to rise from
Bollywood fame to Hollywood power and
still stay true to yourself? In this
bold, funny, and deeply honest
interview, Priyanka Chopra opens up
about breaking stereotypes, navigating
two worlds, and how she finds purpose
beyond fame. But stay with her until the
end because that's when she shares her
most powerful advice yet. Why the best
time to start anything is now.
I know.
Well, you think that you've got talent.
This this incredible woman. She sings,
she dances, she acts, she's an activist,
she's a philanthropist. Welcome,
Priyanka Chopra.
Thank you so much.
It's
Priyanka Chopra.
Thank you so much.
It's
Priyanka Chopra.
Thank you so much.
It's
so good to see you.
Congratulations to
you. 10 years of this incredible summit
of empowering women. Yes.
Yes. Thank
you.
So, listen, Brianka, I do go to India a
lot and Bollywood has some pretty huge
stars, but they never cross over and
make it here. They just don't. You are a
first in that you crossed over and you
became a blazing star in both places.
Aside from obvious things such as your
talent, hard work, drive, all the rest
of it, what do you think were the unique
factors that caused you to really break
out here in the way that you have unlike
so many other very talented actors? Um I
think first of all Tina that I think a a
few quite a few of the actors that I
have spoken to don't really have
ambitions of uh moving out of an
extremely huge movie industry. Bollywood
is one of the biggest producing
industries in the world if not the first
um and it the demographic of Indian
films goes all over the world. So a lot
of my actor friends they they're not
even they're not interested in it. But
the ones who are I think um there is a
little bit of a problem when it comes to
casting of South Asians in Hollywood.
Little bit of a problem.
We are always stereotyped into the kind
of parts we should do and the kind of
parts that you know you see a South
Asian as. Um and they always end up
getting you know amp up your Indian
accent and um few of those things. So I
think what I chose to def do differently
and it's unfortunate that I had to make
that choice was I when I came to America
I decided to play ethnically ambiguous
parts. My first part was Alex Parish.
She was Indian but that was nothing that
had it had nothing to do with the show.
Um then I did Bay Pay Watch. I played
Victoria Leadeds. Then I did Isn't It
Romantic? I was Isabella Stone. But it
took me playing ethnically ambiguous
parts to be main in mainstream pop
culture. And did you sort of
deliberately assue those other kinds of
parts where you said I'm not going to do
that because that's for an Indian girl?
No, I said I'm not going to do that
because then all you will see me is what
I already know I can do. I am Indian. I
don't need my path my parts to um
justify why I can be an actor. And it
would take me doing that to become
mainstream enough now
to actually play
parts where I I am my own ethnicity and
I will not be considered as a niche
actor or or an actor that can only do
that.
Right. I get it. I get it. So what
do you think are the real differences
between you know being a huge star that
you are uh in both places? I mean what's
the difference between doing this in
America and doing this in Bollywood?
Because as you said it was kind of
insular of me in the first place to say
you know why don't people want to be in
America more really or cross over
because as you say Bollywood is a
massive industry and we tend to think
that Hollywood is everything but as you
say it's it's a massive massive
industry. So what is the difference in
being a performer there to being a
performer here? What in terms of power
and privacy and and the roles you're uh
uh offered?
I mean privacy is something
I gave up on a long time ago.
I'm over that. That's not going to
happen. But um I think that culturally
they are both so different. What
Bollywood movies stand for is an
experience. It's magnum. It's colorful.
It it um it has song and dance and
colors and music. And what the work that
I do here are is catering to a different
culture altogether. Like I always got
into trouble whenever I whenever I used
to come from India to work um on corno.
I use my hands a lot to express and my
directors would always be like just turn
it down a little bit. And I never
understood that you know I was like I'm
Indian and I express but um like little
things like that I have to control when
I go beyond when I go back to Bollywood
I have to remember that I need to be
vegan.
But you have all these wonderful
entertainment skills of singing and
dancing and so on. Can you bring that
into our American culture?
Oh give me
another year and a half. I have a few
things up my sleeve.
Oh good. I want to
see that. I want we all want to see
this. Now what about the whole me too
movement? I mean, has that uh hit
Bollywood in the same way that it has in
Hollywood?
Um, yes. I don't think it hit
Bollywood the same way that it hit
Hollywood, but I think there was an
there there was and there still is a
period of time where women found the
courage to be able to speak up things
that they had not spoken up. There were
there are incredible women that stood up
and took on men in a very
in a very
patriarchal country.
Yeah. Um and that
takes an incredible amount of courage
and I extremely applaud that. But then
there are so many other stories that do
get shushed and that do get shut down
because it is patriarchal.
But I think
India has reached a place just like the
rest of the world where women we always
we always had a voice. Nobody heard us
now because of the support that we are
giving each other people don't have the
ability to shut us down. And that's what
happened in India. And it was such an
incredibly powerful thing to see for me
knowing that I I have seen women who've
talked about things that have happened
to them or situations where where they
decide to not talk about it or they'll
say like, you know, I don't want to talk
about it. I don't want to cause scene. I
don't want to bring too much attention
to myself. I'll be blamed. But that's
not the conversation anymore. And just
the fact that the conversation is
shifting is so incredibly powerful. Have
you ever experienced that kind of
harassment yourself?
Um,
I mean this is a question I want to ask
everyone. There is a a bit of a All
right. What's the difference between
being abused, harassed, what are we
talking about? If I talk about sexual
harassment, which I think every woman in
this room probably has. How many has?
That's a pretty full house. So I think
it was harassment and sexual harassment
has be had become a norm with women that
it's okay to just slightly tap a girl on
her bum and it's okay to just make
comments which are which are sort of
unnecessary and not required because
boys will be boys because come on he's
just being a guy. Like we've as women as
society we've had people who we trust
and love say that to us that we never
even questioned it.
Mhm. And slowly, I
think this is probably after, at least
in my lifetime, one of the first times
that I've seen women support each other
so much and come and stand with each
other that now if I have a story, I
don't feel like I'm alone anymore. And
nor am I ashamed of it. And because of
maybe my strength or your strength or
your strength, it'll give some girl
who's sitting in the anonymity of a home
not being able to even have a choice or
a voice the power to be able to do that.
And that's extremely amazing. Now your
mother and father were very big
influences on you and um your dad
encouraged your singing and your mother
uh was very much a role model. She's an
accomplished doctor and your father is a
surgeon right in the army. Um did they
really raise you to be this very
independent young woman? Because so
often in India the girl child isn't
given that same kind of push that the
boys are.
You know India is in such an
amazing precipitate of change right now.
Um and I'm sure you'll notice it. There
is this incredible modernity that exists
in India because of um it being an ever
growing economy. There's so there's such
an interest from all over the world in
India because of what it provides in
terms of entertainment, in terms of
business.
Um so it's at this precipitate
of modernity versus tradition which sort
of clashes a little bit. So you have
and
there's push back too.
Yeah, there's
push back but it's it's an incredible
time. Like my parents for example, I was
raised to be opinionated. I was never
told to be quiet. Um women should be
seen not heard. That was not something
that happened in my house. Everyone in
my at least my in my side of the family
is my family is very matriarchal if I
may say so. Um so I was raised in a very
different environment. My dad never
liked it when I went into the kitchen
because he knew that the environment
that he grew up in, girls were just
relegated to that and he didn't want me
to be to be relegated to that because I
was a little bit of a renegade and I had
crazy dreams and I wanted to, you know,
be so much. So there is that kind of
parenting as well in India. There is
that kind of upbringing as well in
India. But also at the same time, India
is one of the oldest countries in the
world. We're thousands of years old in
terms of our culture. So it's so hard
when you think about changing mindsets
that have existed for centuries. Just to
give you context, America is about 400
years old and it's one of the youngest
countries in the world. So think about
like how far back these ideologies go
and how deep-seated they are in society.
So the fact that India is at the place
where it is where it's giving its women
so much power is is so incredible to see
for me.
Do you feel are you trying to
sort of use your own celebrity to push
those boundaries at all? Do you see that
as a role uh for a celebrity today?
I
do. I feel like a social responsibility
is something we all as individuals need
to feel. But yes, as a public person, I
do see that I I have a platform where
people may not adhere to what I say, but
they will hear me.
Um, I'm a conduit, a
means to an end. Like when I make my
trips with UNICEF or I I do
philanthropy, I'm not physically
changing the world, but I'm bringing
attention to something where
unfortunately people like to read about
me falling on the red carpet a lot more
than anything else that I do.
So I take
that power and actually have bring the
attention onto something that the world
actually needs to talk about. And yes, I
do think that's a social responsibility
of public people and a lot more people
need to do it.
You know, your early sort
of beginnings of of your whole sort of
career propulsion happened with the Miss
India and the Missworld winds, right? In
some ways, you know, it seems almost
anacronistic for this incredibly, you
know, independent young woman raised by
these very sort of rigorous parents with
their careers and so on for you to enter
beauty patterns. I mean, what what was
that about? Was that what drove you to
do that? So the way I see it is that
feminism is all about choices, right?
And every woman, every individual woman
individual choice. So when I was 18,
I was 17 actually when I went to Miss
India. I'd never modeled in my life. I
was I was that was Miss World. But I was
extremely awkward. Um but I liked
winning and
it's my greatest friend and greatest
joy.
But um so when the opportunity came by
from Miss India, it was it's an
extremely prestigious uh pageant in in
India. It's not like I think that the
pageant world is extremely um has a very
bad reputation in the US. Whereas in
India, the pageant world is very
cohesive to the entire personality of a
woman. Um what you look like, how you
speak, especially how much you know. Um,
and that was really there was a lot of
attention that was placed on the on the
substance even for Miss World. And I
feel like for me it was one of the
greatest experiences in my life because
it prepared me to sit in front of
thousand people like this and not be
afraid. It it prepared me to have
conversation with dignitaries of states
and kids in a school and at 18 and 17
set a foundation that made me extremely
worldly wise I guess.
So for me it was
an amazing experience. Well, on
Bollywood used to be, you know, quite an
insular industry um with a few small
families dominating. How hard was it for
you to break into Bollywood? Was that
itself, you know, its own mountain to
climb?
Um yes, Bollywood nepotism and
Bollywood go hand in hand. Um everyone
knows that who knows uh Bollywood, but
there have been a few incredible actors
over the years that have been able to
penetrate that and and make a name for
themselves and then create their own
legacy, which is something I'm hoping to
do. Um, it was very hard. I didn't know
anyone um in in I didn't everyone was
friends with everybody when I joined the
movie business and I'm not really good
at networking. I'm not very good at like
going to the parties and doing the
thing. So, it was a little difficult but
I kind of depended on the fact that I
was not afraid to take on risky parts. I
depended on the fact that I would do
things and and perform in my in my
characters that when people come out and
of a movie they're they're they don't
recognize me, they recognize my
character. I started working on the
craft. I started working on the art of
it. Um, of course I learned dancing and
made sure that I was good at that. But I
think working on yourself sort of gave
me the ability to create those
opportunities. And from my first film
which did really well and I got a lot of
accolades for it, I think it was just
uphill. I just made sure that I didn't
stop working on myself.
Well, now you're
doing a lot of producing. I I don't
think people realize that um there are
22 languages and 720 dialects spoken in
India, right? So you're also producing
um a lot of material for sort of rural
India, right? With which has got these
different dialects and different
languages. Why are you into did you
decide to do that? Well, it's called
regional cinema
and all of almost all of
Indian of the Indian states have
different written and spoken languages.
So I'm not speaking like I don't it's
not a dialect at all. It's like the
alphabet's different, it sounds
different. It's culturally different. So
India is one of the most diverse
countries in the world and each state
has its own almost each state has its
own localized culture and every culture
has storytellers. Storytellers exist
everywhere from our grandparents who
tell us stories in beds in in our bed
which my my grandmother used to do and
you know I had a very vivid imagination
because of that and I felt like I wanted
to be able to give
shed light on local storytellers and
create that in and position them into
having their own industry which
eventually leads us into you know having
a great entertainment business. But I I
just love the fact of supporting people
that may not have the kind of support
without without other people doing it
for them.
Fascinating. Well, you got
married um recently, as I think
everybody knows, to Nick Jonas, uh a
spectacular three-day wedding, which he
Why did he strike such a cord in you
immediately?
I mean, just tell us. We all have a love
story.
Well, I've known him for two
years. Um, but I kind of I don't know. I
wasn't I I didn't think that this would
be what it turned out to be. And that's
maybe my fault. I judged a book by its
cover. But um I think when when I
started actually dating Nick, he
surprised me so much. He's Don't tell
anyone guys even though this is live
streaming.
Um I call him old man Jonas. It's my
name for him. OMJ, he's he's such
he's such a um old soul. Extremely
smart. So good for me because he grounds
me so much. Um I'm like I'm a little bit
I'm a wild child. I do whatever I want
whenever I want and he always supports
me. One of the first things that I think
struck me about him was um we were on a
date and it was you know it was time for
the date to get over. We were a bunch of
friends and I had a meeting and I was
like I was dropping hints to my friends.
They were like, "No, don't go for a
meeting. Just stay." And I was like,
"No, no, no. If someone gives me a
reason enough to cancel it, I'll cancel
it." And he just didn't pick up the
hint. Like, he was just like, I said it
twice. I said it try. Finally, he took
me aside and he was like, "Look, I'm not
stupid. I know what you're trying to do,
but I will never be the one who will
tell you to cancel work because I know
how hard you've worked to be where you
are. So, if you could have canceled it,
you would have done it. I'll take our
friends out for dinner and we'll wait
for you and you finish your meeting and
come back. And I was just like, that's
the first time someone's ever done that.
Well, also so wonderful to know that you
would have somebody who really respected
and understood your own work drive.
Absolutely. I gave me credit for what I
had done. It was just mindblowing for
me. Well, you your wedding was obviously
you played it king-size in in every way.
Hopefully, it'll be the only one that
sounds like
Yes. So, were you were you
making a statement with that because it
was so glorious to watch the way it just
kind of accumulated into this kind of
incredible fiesta that we saw?
Well, I
knew it was going to be 3 days because
Indian Indian weddings do have pre-
rituals. Um, and I knew that both of us
wanted like one wedding in each of our
religions. So, that was two days anyway.
Um, but it all happened so fast. Like we
decided to prep this wedding in October
and we got married 1st of December and
in that one and a half months we were
just like, "Yeah, that sounds great.
Sure, let's get that." And did not
realize it till it was done and we saw
videos and then the build like
oh cool
cool maybe you shouldn't prep this a
little bit more.
So that's why it was
that glorious. Okay. Well, it's it's
pretty hard though for two stars, you
know, with such kind of huge followings
and and all of these work demands to
actually kind of connect and and carve
out time. How do how you how you doing
that? How you carving out time to be
together?
Um, I think that's really
important in any relationship, not just
in a marriage, uh, whether it's with
your friends, with your family, with
your loved ones, is you have to
prioritize what's important to you. Uh,
we make sure whenever we have manageable
schedules that we spend that time with
each other. Like if I'm filming, he'll
come down and he'll stay where I am for
a couple of days because at that time he
has time off or if I have time off and
there's something I can do. We just we
just make sure we don't go more than two
weeks without seeing each other. That's
it.
And you know, you do this work with
UNICEF. Um, are you going to do
philanthropy together? Are you now going
to become uh you know a a couple that
focuses your philanthropy or or keep it
separate?
Both. Yeah.
I think we want to
separate?
Both. Yeah.
I think we want to
separate?
Both. Yeah.
I think we want to
be able to definitely do it together as
well. Um Nick has always been
philanthropic. Um his parents have been,
I have been, my parents have been. We
come from a family where philan phil
philanthropy is not a choice. It's just
what you do. It's it's second nature.
And uh he has individually been doing
it, but we've discussed many things um
that we want to do together. And we know
that we had the ability to. It's in fact
our favorite phrase that we want to
change the world in whatever way we can
somehow.
And what is your focus going to
be? I mean you've been working mostly,
you know, directed towards children,
right? Is that going to be your focus?
For me, it always has been children. It
always has been education, children's
rights. Um I really really believe that
if we pay attention and we don't enough
to the children of the world our the
world becomes a better place in like I
was I was in a few um refugee camps when
I went on trips with UNICEF and um there
were all of these kids who were telling
me their life's dreams right and they're
all in refugee camps for like 5 years
six years and they're like I want to be
an astronaut and I want to be a dentist
and I want to be a teacher.
And I knew when I was sitting in front
of these kids that they wouldn't be all
of that because they don't have an
education. Forget a formal education.
They're in a refugee camp. Thousands and
thousands of these kids. Now think about
the fact that if we don't give them a
pen in their hand. And if the world
doesn't care about the children of the
future, how vulnerable they are to
violence. How vulnerable are they for
someone to put a gun in their hand and
say, "You know what? The world didn't
care about you. Why should you care
about the world? And that's what we need
to stop and protect. I mean, we may not
be able to do it for our own generation
because, you know, people have are
making this world into an extremely
violent place. But I feel like if we if
we target the kids and give them a place
where they feel like they're wanted,
they have the ability to take their
futures into their own hands, it'll just
change the mindset of the world. And I
really really want to be able to do
that. Um the the that is
so good. I knew you were going to get
clapped for that. Um you've also got
involved with Bumble, right? And you to
bringing a dating app to to India. Um
and I'm I'm sort of fascinated about
that because you know India is a place
which is sort of traditionally where
arranged marriages have been such an
important part of its culture. In some
ways, I suppose a dating app is also
about the kind of, you know, the preview
and the choice, you know, and the kind
of it's not about the the chemistry
meeting. It's about choosing and making
a kind of prag pragmatic choice. Do do
you find there is a kind of cultural
resonance for dating apps in India?
Um,
so there are other dating apps in India.
Um, a couple of things. one um like I
said that there is a it's an amazing
time in India with the the meeting of
modernity and tradition that's happening
you have urban India urban culture where
um people are travel they know about the
world everyone knows what's happening
there is a culture of dating definitely
is my parents had a love match not an
arranged match so I mean India is just
so diverse it can't be generalized
second of all bumble I'm very excited
about it and super proud Bumble is not
just a dating app It's a social network.
So, it has Bumble Dating, which is what
it's known for mostly in America, but it
has Bumble BFF. And um the best part
about it is Bumble Biz, which is what
it's it's sort of like whatever
aspirations you might have, you can
connect with people around wherever you
are to help you take those aspirations
forward when you make the first step.
and why it's so amazing for India. When
I met Whitney last year, I was listening
to her talk about Bumble in the US and
the amazing part about it is that it
gives the choice to women. And I can't
speak for every woman in India because
they're all so different. But I know the
power of choice, the power of me having
my choice. And we as we as independent
women in the world, we take it for
granted the ability to have a say in our
own lives. There are so many women
around the world who have no say in when
they'll go to school, when they won't go
to school, who they will marry, what
their lives will look like. And this
sort of gives women a choice to be able
to make a dent in not just their
personal life, but also in their
business and also in friendships. And I
just found that so powerful and profound
and wanted to be able to take it to the
end.
Yeah. So, well, you're such a more
than a triple threat. You're a
quintuplet threat. Uh, Priyanka, what do
you want to do next? I mean, here you
are in the in the US now. You have a
world at your feet. You have this
wonderful new marriage. I mean, what is
the next decade for you in your mind? I
mean, or the next five years. Okay. You
have a game plan. You're very driven. I
know that you're not just
boopping along
thinking about being a wild child,
even
though you pretend you are.
Pretend I am. Okay. Um, I'm not a
planner. Honestly, I really am not. All
I know is
that opportunity
strikes when you don't expect it. The
smarter thing to do is to recognize
opportunity than work so hard and trying
to create it. If you like that's what
I've done all my life like when I came
into America I started doing Quanico I
knew the people I was meeting I decided
I met amazing people that I'm writing a
book this year my editor Pam is here um
I'm I'm producing not just in India and
but I'm also producing in America I'm
developing movies and television that
I'm helping write myself and these are
all things that came out of
opportunities when I had conversations
with people like you just exactly like
our conversation backstage
yeah we've
just planned an India summit in six
cities just in the green room. So,
so
I'm on the train with with the Priyanka
train now, right?
But it really is I
believe that ideas are the currency of
the present. Allow your brain to have
ideas, think about how you can make
those ideas real because this is the
time when we can do it. Never before in
the history of mankind have we been able
to sit in our homes, have an idea, maybe
create it into an app and monetize it.
Right? You can do anything anywhere.
It's just that people hold themselves
back thinking that, oh, I don't know if
I could even even attempt this because I
don't have connections or I you can make
the connections. It's all in the mindset
and that has to be pivoted a little bit.
Well, Priyanka, anything you do, believe
me, you can you can pull it off. So, I
want to thank you enormously for being
with us.
Thank you, Priyanka Chopra.
Join our global community of English
learners absolutely free. Download video
transcripts, listen offline, start our
beginner course, and join live classes
with certified teachers. Access over
1,000 resources to improve your English
faster. Everything's in one place.
Community.englishes.ca.
Let's speak English together.